Eva Hernando

CV

About

I am a very T-shaped service designer, also strong in interaction design and research.

I am a connector of things, people, information who loves making sense out of chaos and multitasking.

I am able to play different roles on a daily basis, from researcher or facilitator to strategist. I embrace any chance to try something new and enjoy constantly challenging myself to expand my skills and continuously learn.

I am motivated by the joy I get when learning something new and when I get to work on projects that will resonate with people.

Originally from Spain, I have lived so far in 5 different countries and have always worked in international and multidisciplinary teams.

In the last 5,5 years I have worked as a service designer, a design researcher and as an interaction designer across different type of projects that include: service innovation, change management, digital transformation or strategic and vision-setting projects.

I have dealt with all kind of challenges that range from how to expand the target user of a smart home app from a mainly nerdy audience to a bigger group, improving the employee experience of large multinational corporation or creating the future vision and the service innovation roadmap for a Pharma.

Interests

People
Behavioral sciences
Cognitive psychology
Sustainability
Emotional intelligence
Public sector
Inclusive design
Social innovation
Emotional sustainability

Skills

Experience design processes and methodologies

Participatory design methodologies and creative facilitation

Conceptualize, conduct and synthesize qualitative research

User task flows and interaction models

User modelling: persona and scenario creation

Opportunity mapping, service & product strategy

Experience

Senior Service designer

Fjord (DE)

Feb 2013- Present

I started at Fjord as a Service designer and become a Senior Service designer in December 2015. During these years I have been based in Fjord Berlin, but I have worked in other Fjord studios as well and travel to many countries to do research and meet with clients.

My work involves uncovering insights and transform them into design opportunities, and eventually design new services. I participate in the scoping and planning of the project and the development of the relationship with the client. I am instrumental in the initial phases of a project from insights, to concept, by guiding how research can be conducted and distilled into actionable design directions and the ideation of service concepts.

UX researcher and service designer intern

Experientia (IT)

May 2012- Nov 2012

Involved in a wide variety of research and strategy projects in industries such as Healthcare, Life-sciences, Technology and Education.

Prepared and conducted ethnographic research on the field and participated in interviews and focus groups, as well as in the research synthesis activities. Organised and facilitated participatory design workshops with clients and users.

Industrial design intern

FLEX/the innovation lab (NL) April 2010- August 2010

My work involved generation of concepts, sketching, visualization, rendering, prototyping, detailing and 3D modelling. I also collaborated with the team of designers in idea generation sessions for different projects.

Industrial designer

Grupo Antolin R&D (ES)
June 2007- July 2008

Designed and created 3D models of automotive components in the Department of Overhead Systems. Produced ceilings, consoles, grab handles and other components for clients such as Jaguar, Audi, or PSA. Responsibilities also included coordinating the design team in India and the central design office in Spain within my projects.

Industries

Utilities, Media, Healthcare, Financial Services, Human resources, Media, Life sciences, Chemicals, Insurances, Public services.

Education

Postgraduate in Human centred innovation and service design

H2i institute by Designit (ES)
October 2011- March 2012

I gained a scholarship to be one of the 16 people per year eligible to do this postgraduate. In addition to the daily lessons by Designit top consultants and other collaborators we did a a real service innovation project for a company. The academic program include design research, strategic design, service design, visual thinking, codesign, storytelling and business design.

MSc Integrated Product Design

Delft University of Technology (NL) September 2008- July 2011

Graduated with a major in product design and with a strong emphasis on design research. Courses I took include: context mapping, creative facilitation and strategy.

During my masters I worked in real challenges for companies and with multidisciplinary teams in which students from all three Design Master's programmes participated.

BSc Product Design

Hogeschool Antwerppen (BE)
September 2006- February 2007

During my bachelor studies I took part in a
Erasmus program for 6 months in Belgium. I
developed a couple of projects in collaboration
with major international companies and follow
courses under a variety of topics such as service
design and universal design.

BSc Industrial design engineering

University of Valladolid (ES) September 2003- June 2006

Studied the disciplines of engineering, design and business, which built the base for future applied logical and analytical thinking.

Continuing education

SXSW- Austin, March 2017.

Creative writing- Madrid, December 2016

UXLx User Experience Lisbon - May 2016

Interactions 16, by IXDA - Helsinki, March 2016

Present with presence- Berlin, February 2016. Rebecca Mackenzie.

UXLx User Experience Lisbon - May 2015

Service Experience camp Berlin- October 2014

Investigative Rehersal. Theatrical improvisation applied to Service Design and Customer Experience, with Adam StJohn Lawrence - October 2014

Behavioural Economics in Action. University of Toronto - December 2013

Visualized.IO Berlin- October 2013

GOOD'13. Network for Global Design
Research- October 2013

A Beginner's Guide to Irrational Behavior.

Duke University - May 2013

Cocreation & Codesign workshop by Liz Sanders - March 2012

Languages

Spanish - native

English - advanced

Italian - advanced

German - upper intermediate

Contact

e.hernandomartin@gmail.com DE +491755767478